<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <description>The design portfolio of Eric Moe.</description>
    <link>https://ericmoe.co</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ericmoe.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 09:24:20 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 09:24:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>


        <item>
            <title>Tweet Famous</title>
            <description>My most goofy tweet gone viral...</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 10:00:50 -0500</pubDate>
            <link>https://ericmoe.co/blog/2017/09/11/tweet.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ericmoe.co/blog/2017/09/11/tweet.html</guid>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;I sincerely doubt that this is blog-worthy, but I thought I might as well make a post to commemorate this blunder permanently. If you are familiar with my work or this site, you might have noticed the abundance of social media outlets I use to cross-post my design work. Occasionally I run into a few bugs  as evident by this woefully cropped tweet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;A few more web experiments, this one was to illustrate Drunk Drivers/Killer Whales by Car Seat Headrest. More at &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/xsBhsUuUAc&quot;&gt;https://t.co/xsBhsUuUAc&lt;/a&gt;... &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/dy3qiFPZgk&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/dy3qiFPZgk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Eric Moe (@geomoetric) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/geomoetric/status/907250198069510145&quot;&gt;September 11, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I realized my mistake in mere hours, I did not clue into how I was amassing so many likes so quickly. Is my social media strategy completely bonkers? Should I just post nonsensical tweets? Is &lt;a href=&quot;ericmoe.co/porf&quot;&gt;ericmoe.co/porf&lt;/a&gt; a viable domain name?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/headrest-1008by1008-e4fbbd.png&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 42em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 42em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/headrest-672by672-e4fbbd.png&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 42em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/headrest-621by621-e4fbbd.png&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 32em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 32em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/headrest-414by414-e4fbbd.png&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 32em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/headrest-483by483-e4fbbd.png&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/headrest-322by322-e4fbbd.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img data-src=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/headrest-322by322-e4fbbd.png&quot; class=&quot;lazyload col three&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;/img/lq.png&quot; alt=&quot;the tweet&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope, just somehow got re-tweeted by critically acclaimed Will Toledo of &lt;a href=&quot;https://carseatheadrest.bandcamp.com/&quot;&gt;Car Seat Headrest&lt;/a&gt;. Since this is my only piece of design I would remotely consider “fan art,” I guess I have peaked and it’s time to quit while ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            <image>
                <url>https://ericmoe.co/img/whale.png</url>
                <title>Tweet Famous</title>
                <link>https://ericmoe.co/blog/2017/09/11/tweet.html</link>
            </image>
            <enclosure url="https://ericmoe.co/img/whale.png"  type="audio/mpeg" />
            
            <category>twitter</category>
            
            <category>carseatheadrest</category>
            
            
            <category>blog</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Thank You Graphic Ancestors</title>
            <description>A &quot;Graphic Means&quot; Review</description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 22:11:41 -0500</pubDate>
            <link>https://ericmoe.co/blog/2017/09/10/graphic-means.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ericmoe.co/blog/2017/09/10/graphic-means.html</guid>
            <content>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/157620840&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not have done it! There’s no question; I would have taken one class and immediately switched out of design school. What would be the final straw? Setting the type by hand? Memorizing typographic ratios? Cutting out all that gosh darned acetate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am talking about graphic design before the advent of the computer, the subject of the new documentary &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.graphicmeans.com/&quot;&gt;“Graphic Means”&lt;/a&gt; by Briar Levit. I was fortunate enough to see a screening at the State Theatre put on by AIGA Austin and the University of Texas at Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film guides the viewer through 100 years of design history and practice. From hot type set in molten lead, to cold type beamed through film negatives, and the ultimate takeover of the computer, it is clear that design skills have changed throughout the ages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Graphic Means” has rattled around my brain far longer than it had any right too. The film is so comfortable in its skin— at times a parade of trade videos and cheery innovation lining up neat and tidy, design technology advancing without a care. You cannot help but look back and think they really knew how to design back in the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/means-web-1008by504-624f36.png&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 42em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 42em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/means-web-672by336-624f36.png&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 42em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/means-web-621by311-624f36.png&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 32em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 32em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/means-web-414by207-624f36.png&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 32em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/means-web-483by242-624f36.png&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source data-srcset=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/means-web-322by161-624f36.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img data-src=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/generated/means-web-322by161-624f36.png&quot; class=&quot;lazyload col three&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;/img/lq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cut and paste&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, cutting and pasting, shooting and photographing, typesetting and printing— the antique design process reveals itself to be meticulous work. At one point, an animation illustrates over a dozen steps the designer would go through to print an all text newspaper! All the while the designer often had no idea what the final product would look like, meaning their work was the result of internal vision and rote precision alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any other age, these designers would have been masters of their craft deserving a place in a pantheon of gifted artists. The quiet tragedy of this documentary was that the design technology outpaced its operators, leaving many artisans out of a job or forced to retrain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A scene from the last day of hot type at the New York Times shows these craftsmen, whom we saw at the top of their game just years earlier, relegated to the dustbin of history in real time. Their somber faces seemed far away from their hands moving like lighting over piles of metal type. A board in the press room reads “The end of an era. It was good while it lasted. Crying won’t help.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/127605643?byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had been born even 20 years earlier, I would have struggled with the technical limitations of the field. I am grateful to be the beneficiary of a century of innovation and upheaval in the design field. If nothing else, it is clearer than ever that design will continue to evolve with or without me as I continue my education and career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, some constants present themselves throughout the film. People desire their ideas to be set to image and type, and they enlist designers to fulfill those needs. Both early adopters and hardline traditionalists continue to populate the design field. No matter where the technology goes in the future, human relationships enable and manifest themselves through design both then and now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            <image>
                <url>https://ericmoe.co/img/means-web.png</url>
                <title>Thank You Graphic Ancestors</title>
                <link>https://ericmoe.co/blog/2017/09/10/graphic-means.html</link>
            </image>
            <enclosure url="https://ericmoe.co/img/means-web.png"  type="audio/mpeg" />
            
            <category>graphicmeans</category>
            
            <category>design</category>
            
            <category>retro</category>
            
            
            <category>blog</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Donezo! 2016 Fall Semester in Review</title>
            <description>Check out what I've been up to this semester. Two jobs, new projects, and somehow straight A's.</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>https://ericmoe.co/blog/2016/12/19/semester-review.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ericmoe.co/blog/2016/12/19/semester-review.html</guid>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; src=&quot;/img/donezoweb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dust has settled on the Fall Semester— and what a semester it’s been. Fall 2016 was officially the beginning of my design coursework at UT. Having completed all my preliminary work, I was free to take courses on graphic design, typography, and product design. On top of that, I worked two jobs, finished this website, and completed some top notch design work that I will post soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been eagerly awaiting college design classes since the seventh grade, and I am happy to report that all three were fantastic. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.husbandmen.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JimJames Walker’s&lt;/a&gt; Images in Communication was my straight graphic design course, covering Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, RAW photography, and Indesign, to name a few programs. Alyson Beaton’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://abeatontype.wordpress.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Typography I&lt;/a&gt; class had me putting layouts and books together with my favorite fonts. I even designed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ericmoe.co/portfolio/2016-11-28-razor-website/&quot;&gt;new kind of razor&lt;/a&gt; for Kate Catterall’s Introduction to Design Thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I wrapped up my job at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brendathompson.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brenda Thompson Communications&lt;/a&gt;. Stay tuned for a post about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://issuu.com/lifeandletters/docs/ll_fall2016_issu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Life and Letters Magazine&lt;/a&gt; illustrations I did for UT Liberal Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big milestone this semester was the sophomore review. In what seemed like the busiest day of my life, I presented my design pieces to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://art.utexas.edu/academics/design-faculty&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UT design faculty&lt;/a&gt; for evaluation. We had a great conversation, the feedback was helpful, and I am happy to report that I am on track to graduate. I also added this “script” I prepared that might give you an idea of how it went down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good Morning! My name is Eric Moe, and I am thrilled to be a sophomore Design major, even at 8 AM! So I believe I was asked to pick two favorite pieces, or two pieces to contextualize my design practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I cannot choose a favorite child so I am choosing my source book as one of my pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It contains work from all of my classes and from my design jobs at Brenda Thompson Communications and UT liberal Arts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This book is based on old field guides. I gravitate toward classic techniques and mid-century aesthetics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am interested in how I could apply classic craft, like sign painting, Rockwell-esque illustration, and modernist forms in twenty-first-century contexts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This brings me to my second piece, my design website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I hand coded this in my free time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s very simple— a static site generator with some automated social media processes, but I am beaming with pride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It has also established a precedent for how my design practice should continue outside of the classroom, and how I apply what I am learning to my personal work.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For example, I use Alyson’s lessons on type to create a readable site,&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I use Jim’s training on visual clarity to streamline navigation.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I use Kate’s worldview exercises to establish what will make my online presence stand out in the void.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I would like to thank you for your time and take any questions about my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• What do you find most interesting about design?
&lt;strong&gt;The positive effects it has on people’s lives.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• What kind of designer do you think you’d like to be?
&lt;strong&gt;I would like to be a designer who embraces the 21st-century technology with 20th-century skill.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• If you could change the works on display, what changes would you make?
&lt;strong&gt;I honestly would rather start a new work entirely than change an old one. I have to complete pieces. There need to be periods and exclamation marks in my life, not just commas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• What have you learned thus far in the design program and what would you like to learn in the future? &lt;strong&gt;This program has taught me how to design on a professional level. Yes, I knew color composition and adobe illustrator going into this program— UT elevated the way I think and the way I work to be even more efficient and creative. I hope to learn more tech and web related design mediums&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Do you have any questions for the faculty? &lt;strong&gt;What are your favorite Design Books?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            <image>
                <url>https://ericmoe.co/img/donezoweb.jpg</url>
                <title>Donezo! 2016 Fall Semester in Review</title>
                <link>https://ericmoe.co/blog/2016/12/19/semester-review.html</link>
            </image>
            <enclosure url="https://ericmoe.co/img/donezoweb.jpg"  type="audio/mpeg" />
            
            <category>donezo</category>
            
            
            <category>blog</category>
            
        </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
