<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <description>The design portfolio of Eric Moe.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 22:17:28 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 22:17:28 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.0</generator>
    
    
    
    
    
      
     
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Ways of Seeing</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/tackArtboard%205.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/tackArtboard%203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/tackArtboard%204.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/tackArtboard%201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/tackArtboard%202.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was assigned a tack and my project was to make the tack represent a list of words assigned to us. I was interested in framing the tack with human anatomy, so I am the subject of these photos. Quick shout out to my father, Thomas Moe, who lent me his astounding camera to take these shots. Oh man, I have to get that camera back to him before he gets mad now that I think of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;nervous&quot;&gt;Nervous&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/tackArtboard%205.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I proposed this photo at a different angle, and my classmates said it looked fake. I rotated it 95° and they said they loved the new photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;curious&quot;&gt;Curious&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/tackArtboard%203.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a rough shoot because of the direct light in my eyes. I ended up editing out the tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tender&quot;&gt;Tender&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/tackArtboard%204.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has science gone too far? Did my father’s camera capture too much detail in this shot?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;clumsy&quot;&gt;Clumsy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/tackArtboard%201.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took 200 photos of this shot. The words “motion photography” bring flashbacks of flashbulbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;loud&quot;&gt;Loud&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/tackArtboard%202.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of my classmates said that “snug” would be a better fit for this pic. I worry about these people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did the bulk of my photography on the evening of November 8th, so imagine me throwing tacks while listening to election returns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 01:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-ways-of-seeing/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-ways-of-seeing/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>A-Z Austin Type</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/ACL.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems I am haunted by a specter of music festivals, specifically Austin City Limits Festival. I dislike derivative work on principle— to my knowledge I have not done anything resembling fan-art since the seventh grade. It seems limiting to be bound to someone else’s ideas and super cringy without proper execution.
That being said, I am a sucker for working within a brand identity or typographical framework. Just today I was excitedly showing my recreation of the New York Time’s Op-Ed page to my classmates (most of whom have never read an Op-Ed I suspect). I am the same sucker for Austin City Limits— I love the type, the colors, the branding, and of course the music that I enjoy every year. 
Last year I found myself assigned to a project right on the heels of the fest, and I thought to myself, “Hey, I have the photos and the inspiration, I will just make an ACL-centric poster.” Learning nothing from the year prior, I decided to collect typography during my weekend at Zilker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/ACL Map2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a photo of a band and no one bats an eye. Take a photo of typography at a music festival and everyone looses their minds. I love this selection of typography, but the feeling was not mutual even within the class. When I dropped the idea of using my photos in my poster, my type teacher’s eyes widened to a panic as the objections sputtered out. Look, I get it— the photos are rough, but a little photoshop magic would settle this straight away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/ACLalt.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should take a second to step back and explain the project. We were supposed to find letters around Austin, Texas for use in an alphabetical poster. Thats how it began at least— it seemed as the project went on the instructions got looser and the expectations rose. Here is just one of many rejected drafts— I suppose that this piece was sort of designed by committee, but hey, I’m here to please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My classmates helped me decide on a map as my final organizational structure. Each letter is placed where it can be located in the fest, and the key to the right side denotes what word the letter was part of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-austin-acl-type/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-austin-acl-type/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Editorial Spreads</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a project made for someone who has read a newspaper since the first grade. Our prompt was to take Op-Ed articles without formatting, set them in InDesign, and provide editorial illustrations. Below are my final designs, set in the style of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2010/09/25/opinion/opedat40-illustration.html?_r=1&amp;amp;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;New York Times Op-Ed page&lt;/a&gt;. Nothing quite like that &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=tE4EAAAAMBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA152&amp;amp;dq=%22the+gray+lady%22+%22new+york+times%22&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=tokrT_DMKK7aiQKwttTgCg&amp;amp;ved=0CDwQ6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22the%20gray%20lady%22%20%22new%20york%20times%22&amp;amp;f=false&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Grey Lady&lt;/a&gt; combo of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myfonts.com/fonts/bitstream/imperial/?refby=MarkFonts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Imperial&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myfonts.com/fonts/bitstream/bookman/?refby=MarkFonts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bookman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-algorithms-taste-in-wine-is-better-than-yours&quot;&gt;This Algorithm’s Taste in Wine is Better than Yours&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This design started as a goofy doodle that eventually materialized as a boozy robot and his trusty human companion. I think the funky print effect is the better treatment between the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/Editorial4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/Editorial1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/editorialspread2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/editorialspread3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-doll-in-the-blue-pantsuit&quot;&gt;The Doll in the Blue Pantsuit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this op-ed, the imagery of the doll seemed too on the nose for my purposes, so I used doll packaging as the foundation of the piece. It is meant to be a narrative that describes the popular demand each candidate experienced through that American pastime of vicious shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/Editorial3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/editorialspread.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!--
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/editorialspread.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/editorialspread2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/editorialspread3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
	Caption photos easily. On the left, a road goes through a tunnel. Middle, leaves artistically fall in a hipster photoshoot. Right, in another hipster photoshoot, a lumberjack grasps a handful of pine needles.
&lt;/div&gt;
--&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-editorial/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-editorial/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Political Grid Posters</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/ERIC MOE.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
One fun fact about this piece— the blue is the same hex value as the blue on the US flag (#002868).
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am afraid I am an internally political person. Blame it on apolitical parents, midwestern sensibilities, a hesitation to argue without facts— I rarely voice my opinions through my art. The re-approptiation grid project aimed to let my political classmates vent their views in a creative way while learning about visual grid structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can see a detail of my diagonal halftones. It’s a technique I have used in the past but I find myself gravitating toward it again and again. There is something magical about an image that appears only at the right distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I think that political art easily alienates and dates your work. Therefore, this message of voter empowerment seemed to fit my centrist leanings while sharing a message that everyone can get behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished this project before the election of the 45th President of the United States. I think about that critique when my classmates voiced their political opinions at great length only to reveal that a majority had failed to register to vote. I think about the five or so students that I got to vote and the outcome in Austin vs that of the US. I think back to the excitement I had for the political process I had then and the dread I feel looking at my news feed today. I consider where our 45th president would go within this diverse spread of this poster— whether he has a place in this America or whether I have a place in his America.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-reappropriation-grid/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-reappropriation-grid/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Spec Society</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/soc1.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first substantial project in Typography One was to set Guy Debord’s &lt;em&gt;The Society of the Spectacle&lt;/em&gt;. I had a similar idea before we were assigned this project— as a way to learn InDesign I would set an obscure book and possibly self publish. 
In some ways I am relieved that this project beat me to the punch. For one thing, my plan was to do this in June, and since I had not started it by the time it was assigned in September, my grades were an obvious motivating factor. The only thing I found to be un-motivating was the subject matter. I had considered using Italo Calvino’s &lt;em&gt;Invisible Cities&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Cloud of Unknowing&lt;/em&gt; as my filler text. &lt;em&gt;The Society of the Spectacle&lt;/em&gt;’s blithering nonsense failed to resonate with me as my curated nonsense did. Maybe I am not as much of a communist as my &lt;del&gt;classmates&lt;/del&gt; comrades are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/soc2.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/spectacle.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see this reflected in my front cover. I went for a maximal design with a dusty third edition paperback connotation. If the material was about the excesses of capitalism, my plan was to create a cover that utilized excess to its full ability. In this respect I believe I am successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/spectacle2.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above you will see a classic type exercise in which young design students label the various parts of the font. Poster Bodoni and Din are an interesting combo, maybe I will use them again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/spectacle3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In keeping with the theme of my cover, I chose to make my spreads an excess of scale. In placing a text about efficiency, I imagine a book that wastes plentiful printing area. Perhaps this highlights the concerns of the text, perhaps it renders it impotent. The important thing is that the reader finds themselves considering the form of the typography in addition to the book claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not know if I still stand by the decision to set body copy in a monospace font. But as you can see within this book and within my website project featured later— I still like block serif fonts. No apologies!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/soc3.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you have to print something to know how it truly looks. Sometimes you even have to print something, re-photograph it, and print it again in a sample book. I think a better color scheme, beyond our basic CMYK, would really finish this piece correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-society-of-spectacle/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-society-of-spectacle/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Thunder&lt;wbr&gt;Cloud</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/infog.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the largest projects I had at Brenda Thompson Communications was creating material for &lt;a href=&quot;http://thundercloud.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thundercloud Subs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This piece is an infographic on various figures from the charity run that might give anyone unfamiliar with the trot the context for all my other designs. Ultimately, I believe that this square layout limited me, but perhaps If I had the ability to devote more time to it things would have been different. 
&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/infog2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the tradition of the ThunderCloud Subs Turkey Trot Art Contest, but that hand drawn turkey really does not make sense in the context of the infographic. Half of the icons were graciously borrowed from the noun project, specifically &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/uberux/collection/new-years-resolutions/?i=324691&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Do charity by Guilherme Simoes from the Noun Project&lt;/a&gt;. Can you tell which ones I created?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/Tcloud-Export%20copy%206.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, here are a few Instagram photos I created for ThunderCloud Subs picnic campaign. It is no secret that Austin is known for its amazing parks, and it was fun to run around the city, sandwich in tow, on behalf of TCloud. Most of these pics hail from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austinchronicle.com/news/2009-04-17/767852/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;East Austin pocket parks&lt;/a&gt;, and of course, &lt;a href=&quot;http://austintexas.gov/department/zilker-metropolitan-park&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zilker&lt;/a&gt; is featured prominently. The only snafu I encountered on this adventure was the sheer number of dogs interested in my sandwiches!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/Tcloud-Export%20copy%204.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/Tcloud-Export%20copy%205.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/Tcloud-Export%20copy%207.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/Tcloud-Export.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/Tcloud-Export%20copy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/Tcloud-Export%20copy%203.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-turkey-trot/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-23-turkey-trot/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>UT Xmas Card</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/utxmas2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;UT Xmas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truthfully I did not do much on this card, yet it remains one of my favorites. Each of these photos is from one of the old cactus yearbooks that we keep on the shelves in my office in the College of Liberal Arts. A lot of work goes into finding the seven or so notable snow days in the history of UT photojournalism— while questionable minstrel shows and bygone student organizations populated most pages, I found two photos that seemed to match what we wanted to convey in a Christmas Card for donors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This photos is interesting for a few reasons. I think that the snowman’s face is a little too dirty, yet my immediate boss disagrees, and my other boss agrees with me! As of writing this the conflict is not resolved, but maybe my position is changing? I see this snowman as no longer creepy. I see this snowman as students attempting to create their anonymous professor’s crabby visage in snow. If this mockery is the case, I am one hundred percent onboard to keep the photo just the way it is.
&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/utxmas3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;UT Xmas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This second photo is a great way to frame the end of the semester. Just looking at it gives me that same sense of peace and tranquility a quiet day on campus will. Its true, I edited these pictures—adjusted the colors, fixed tears and creases, that sort of thing—but from the moment I opened the cactus I hoped that my boss would use this one for the card.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 13:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-30-ut-xmas-card/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-30-ut-xmas-card/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Merry Xmas from Moe!</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/xmas.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/2016xmas.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy &lt;em&gt;(insert winter holiday here)&lt;/em&gt; from your friend Eric Moe! This year I designed a Christmas postcard I sent to friends and family. Lots of positive feedback and holiday wishes, but a few people asked me who I hired to illustrate my card (🙄). This was a quick one— I submitted the design for print and sent out my physical copies within a week of Christmas. I am posting it today because my illustration of the Barton Springs Polar Bear Plunge happens tomorrow! If you want to see me participate, check out &lt;a href=&quot;/geomoetric/&quot;&gt;@geomoetric&lt;/a&gt; for the winter shenanigans.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-31-xmas-card/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-12-31-xmas-card/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Guide to Eric Moe</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/guide1.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my final project from fall Typography I. My predicament is that the project was a source book— an overview of my entire semester. So how do I summarize a project that exists as a summary? Furthermore, how do I provide insightful commentary when all the rigmarole I wrote inside the book served double duty on this blog?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/guidesp.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well at least I can show off these intro pages. You can find the various chapters and projects in a similar format on my &lt;a href=&quot;/archive/&quot;&gt;archives&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/guidesp2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little introductory commentary by my brother and I. My philosophy on these intro pages was that I did not want to waste precious design material before diving into the semester. I figured that I would include a few goofy pictures of myself at twenty, for something to look back upon, and as a joke for my classmates in the final critique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/guidesp3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme I pursued with this project was “classic guide book”. Inspired by the likes of &lt;a href=&quot;https://fieldnotesbrand.com/products/drive&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Field Notes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/the-green-book/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Green Books&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.michaelschwab.com/posters.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Michael Schwab Illustrations&lt;/a&gt;. The icons above are from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/edward/collection/national-park-service/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;US Parks Service&lt;/a&gt; and denote assignments and themes on each project page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/guide3.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/guide4.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, I got to create the book in real life! It miraculously exists in this french folded form  thanks to Elmer’s glue and the book press I believe I used incorrectly. I love the way it turned out and I hope more print media is in my future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2017-01-13-guide-book/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2017-01-13-guide-book/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>UT Annual Impact Report</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/utfall6.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the behemoth of the fall 2016 semester— at my UT job, this was top priority for two months. The Annual Impact Report summarizes donor support and scholarly initiatives of the school year for UT’s very own Department of Liberal Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/utfall8.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I handled the beginings of this project and the wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allenquigley.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Allen Quigley&lt;/a&gt; finished it. Although pretty corporate and design-by-committee, I felt as though I learned a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/utfall7.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truthfully, this project was an InDesign trial by fire. The scope and breadth of this project allowed me to hone my skills, and it always feels good to have a project go to press.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2017-01-10-ut-annual-impact/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2017-01-10-ut-annual-impact/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Razor Project</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/sabre5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you did not know, I am a genetic Scandinavian anomaly in this great state of Texas. My body thinks we’re about to hook up the reindeer to go ice-fishing, yet outside it has not been sub 70 in the whole month of November. 
So when we were tasked with redesigning a common tool, I scratched my freshly shaved stubble and realized it had to be the razor. Not just any razor either, my razor of choice in my 8 years of shaving— the safety razor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/razor3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I compared electric, straight, disposable, multi-blade, and safety razors on a number of metrics, and the humble safety razor was the clear winner. So why is the safety razor a relict of a bygone age if it is so effective?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/razor2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My design aims to update the safety razor for modern shaving habits. A grooved grip and weighted head let the razor fall at a perfect 45° angle on your face. Both the razor and the stand it ships with reduce waste caused by manufacturing and planned obsolescence. All in all, these adjustments and countless other subtleties will support a fantastic shave every time— isn’t that what razors are all about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/razor5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, I was not lying about the beard! This is what the 3D print of my razor looks like. In the end I created sixteen or so prints of my razor. Sometimes, the prints themselves failed, rendering strange, contorted death blades. Other times, my model would be incorrect. I realized too late that my razor did not hold standard double-sided blades— an issue promptly fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/razor4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I envision this razor cast in stainless steel. If I were to take this concept farther, it would be my hope that this realized razor would be a treasured item for men and women to keep their entire lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/sabre2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/sabre3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/sabre4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;example image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few shots from my website proposal you can find &lt;a href=&quot;/portfolio/2016-11-28-razor-website/&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; Truthfully, I put this together very quickly, but as an exercise in branding, lean development, and late night achievement, I believe it is successful.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2017-01-11-razor-project/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2017-01-11-razor-project/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Life &amp; Letters Fall 2016</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/utfall9.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an unexpected project. As I was recovering from the intense Impact Report, I was given what seemed like a tiny assignment for UT’s own Liberal Arts Magazine. No, I was not given the cover of &lt;a href=&quot;http://cenjun.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Life &amp;amp; Letters&lt;/a&gt;—thanks for nothing Jun Cen—but the editorial illustration has been a worthwhile experience I hope to pursue in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/ll1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a little collab between &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allenquigley.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Allen Quigley&lt;/a&gt; and I. He covered the colors while I created the icons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/ll4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The assignments kept coming, and I felt this illustration of a map girl beckoned back to an older style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/ll5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny Franks has seen better days, but I believe this quick illustration turned out well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/ll2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the bottom left corner you will find another quick illustration. Notice the coat hanger question mark— perhapst its too subtle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/ll3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These backpacks existed in several different forms atop several different backgrounds before ultimately going in a subtle direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;read-the-full-issue-belowhttpsissuucomlifeandlettersdocsllfall2016issutargetblank&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issuu.com/lifeandletters/docs/ll_fall2016_issu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read the full issue below.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%; height:500px;&quot; src=&quot;//e.issuu.com/embed.html#9815718/43034476&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!--
&lt;div data-configid=&quot;9815718/43034476&quot; style=&quot;width:100%; height:500px;&quot; class=&quot;issuuembed&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//e.issuu.com/embed.js&quot; async=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
--&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2017-01-13-life-letters/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2017-01-13-life-letters/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Westie Stickers</title>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;you-can-check-out-the-stickers-in-the-imessage-storehttpsitunesapplecomusappwestie-stickersid1193470178mt8targetblank&quot;&gt;You can check out the stickers in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/westie-stickers/id1193470178?mt=8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iMessage store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/1024x768.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working for the first time in the Apple development environment, I produced my humble sticker pack. These were both an opportunity to practice with Apple, and a way to immortalize a cheeky dog named Bolt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b11.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b12.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b13.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b14.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b15.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b16.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b17.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b18.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b19.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b20.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b21.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b22.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b23.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b24.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b25.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b26.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b27.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/img/b28.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;westie sticker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 20:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2017-01-14-westie/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2017-01-14-westie/</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    

    

    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Donezo! 2016 Fall Semester in Review</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/donezoweb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dust has settled on the Fall Semester— and what a semester it’s been. Fall 2016 was officially the beginning of my design coursework at UT. Having completed all my preliminary work, I was free to take courses on graphic design, typography, and product design. On top of that, I worked two jobs, finished this website, and completed some top notch design work that I will post soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been eagerly awaiting college design classes since the seventh grade, and I am happy to report that all three were fantastic. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.husbandmen.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JimJames Walker’s&lt;/a&gt; Images in Communication was my straight graphic design course, covering Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, RAW photography, and Indesign, to name a few programs. Alyson Beaton’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://abeatontype.wordpress.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Typography I&lt;/a&gt; class had me putting layouts and books together with my favorite fonts. I even designed a &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-11-28-razor-website/&quot;&gt;new kind of razor&lt;/a&gt; for Kate Catterall’s Introduction to Design Thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I wrapped up my job at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brendathompson.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brenda Thompson Communications&lt;/a&gt;. Stay tuned for a post about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://issuu.com/lifeandletters/docs/ll_fall2016_issu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Life and Letters Magazine&lt;/a&gt; illustrations I did for UT Liberal Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big milestone this semester was the sophomore review. In what seemed like the busiest day of my life, I presented my design pieces to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://art.utexas.edu/academics/design-faculty&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UT design faculty&lt;/a&gt; for evaluation. We had a great conversation, the feedback was helpful, and I am happy to report that I am on track to graduate. I also added this “script” I prepared that might give you an idea of how it went down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good Morning! My name is Eric Moe, and I am thrilled to be a sophomore Design major, even at 8 AM! So I believe I was asked to pick two favorite pieces, or two pieces to contextualize my design practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I cannot choose a favorite child so I am choosing my source book as one of my pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It contains work from all of my classes and from my design jobs at Brenda Thompson Communications and UT liberal Arts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This book is based on old field guides. I gravitate toward classic techniques and mid-century aesthetics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am interested in how I could apply classic craft, like sign painting, Rockwell-esque illustration, and modernist forms in twenty-first-century contexts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This brings me to my second piece, my design website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I hand coded this in my free time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s very simple— a static site generator with some automated social media processes, but I am beaming with pride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It has also established a precedent for how my design practice should continue outside of the classroom, and how I apply what I am learning to my personal work.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For example, I use Alyson’s lessons on type to create a readable site,&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I use Jim’s training on visual clarity to streamline navigation.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I use Kate’s worldview exercises to establish what will make my online presence stand out in the void.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I would like to thank you for your time and take any questions about my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• What do you find most interesting about design?
&lt;strong&gt;The positive effects it has on people’s lives.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• What kind of designer do you think you’d like to be?
&lt;strong&gt;I would like to be a designer who embraces the 21st-century technology with 20th-century skill.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• If you could change the works on display, what changes would you make?
&lt;strong&gt;I honestly would rather start a new work entirely than change an old one. I have to complete pieces. There need to be periods and exclamation marks in my life, not just commas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• What have you learned thus far in the design program and what would you like to learn in the future? &lt;strong&gt;This program has taught me how to design on a professional level. Yes, I knew color composition and adobe illustrator going into this program— UT elevated the way I think and the way I work to be even more efficient and creative. I hope to learn more tech and web related design mediums&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Do you have any questions for the faculty? &lt;strong&gt;What are your favorite Design Books?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/19/semester-review.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/19/semester-review.html</guid>
            
            <category>donezo</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
  </channel>
</rss>
