<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twitter</title>
    <description>The design portfolio of Eric Moe.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 17:07:03 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 17:07:03 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.0</generator>
    
      
     
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    

    
        

        

        
        <item>
            <title>Donezo! 2016 Fall Semester in Review</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/img/donezoweb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dust has settled on the Fall Semester— and what a semester it’s been. Fall 2016 was officially the beginning of my design coursework at UT. Having completed all my preliminary work, I was free to take courses on graphic design, typography, and product design. On top of that, I worked two jobs, finished this website, and completed some top notch design work that I will post soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been eagerly awaiting college design classes since the seventh grade, and I am happy to report that all three were fantastic. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.husbandmen.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JimJames Walker’s&lt;/a&gt; Images in Communication was my straight graphic design course, covering Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, RAW photography, and Indesign, to name a few programs. Alyson Beaton’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://abeatontype.wordpress.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Typography I&lt;/a&gt; class had me putting layouts and books together with my favorite fonts. I even designed a &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2016-11-28-razor-website/&quot;&gt;new kind of razor&lt;/a&gt; for Kate Catterall’s Introduction to Design Thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I wrapped up my job at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brendathompson.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brenda Thompson Communications&lt;/a&gt;. Stay tuned for a post about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://issuu.com/lifeandletters/docs/ll_fall2016_issu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Life and Letters Magazine&lt;/a&gt; illustrations I did for UT Liberal Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big milestone this semester was the sophomore review. In what seemed like the busiest day of my life, I presented my design pieces to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://art.utexas.edu/academics/design-faculty&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UT design faculty&lt;/a&gt; for evaluation. We had a great conversation, the feedback was helpful, and I am happy to report that I am on track to graduate. I also added this “script” I prepared that might give you an idea of how it went down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good Morning! My name is Eric Moe, and I am thrilled to be a sophomore Design major, even at 8 AM! So I believe I was asked to pick two favorite pieces, or two pieces to contextualize my design practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I cannot choose a favorite child so I am choosing my source book as one of my pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It contains work from all of my classes and from my design jobs at Brenda Thompson Communications and UT liberal Arts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This book is based on old field guides. I gravitate toward classic techniques and mid-century aesthetics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am interested in how I could apply classic craft, like sign painting, Rockwell-esque illustration, and modernist forms in twenty-first-century contexts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This brings me to my second piece, my design website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I hand coded this in my free time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s very simple— a static site generator with some automated social media processes, but I am beaming with pride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It has also established a precedent for how my design practice should continue outside of the classroom, and how I apply what I am learning to my personal work.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For example, I use Alyson’s lessons on type to create a readable site,&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I use Jim’s training on visual clarity to streamline navigation.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I use Kate’s worldview exercises to establish what will make my online presence stand out in the void.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I would like to thank you for your time and take any questions about my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• What do you find most interesting about design?
&lt;strong&gt;The positive effects it has on people’s lives.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• What kind of designer do you think you’d like to be?
&lt;strong&gt;I would like to be a designer who embraces the 21st-century technology with 20th-century skill.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• If you could change the works on display, what changes would you make?
&lt;strong&gt;I honestly would rather start a new work entirely than change an old one. I have to complete pieces. There need to be periods and exclamation marks in my life, not just commas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• What have you learned thus far in the design program and what would you like to learn in the future? &lt;strong&gt;This program has taught me how to design on a professional level. Yes, I knew color composition and adobe illustrator going into this program— UT elevated the way I think and the way I work to be even more efficient and creative. I hope to learn more tech and web related design mediums&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Do you have any questions for the faculty? &lt;strong&gt;What are your favorite Design Books?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/19/semester-review.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/19/semester-review.html</guid>
            
            <category>donezo</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
    
  </channel>
</rss>
